{
  "level1": [
    {
      "question_id": 1,
      "question_text": "Which of the following is generally used for performing tasks like creating the structure of the relations, deleting relation?",
      "choice1": "DML(Data Manipulation Language)",
      "choice2": "Query",
      "choice3": "Relational Schema",
      "choice4": "DDL(Data Definition Language)",
      "correct_ans": "DDL(Data Definition Language)",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 2,
      "question_text": "Which of the following provides the ability to query information from the database and insert tuples into, delete tuples from, and modify tuples in the database?",
      "choice1": "DML(Data Manipulation Language)",
      "choice2": "DDL(Data Definition Language)",
      "choice3": "Query",
      "choice4": "Relational Schema",
      "correct_ans": "DML(Data Manipulation Language)",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 3,
      "question_text": "The given Query can also be replaced with_______:\nSELECT name, course_id\nFROM instructor, teaches\nWHERE instructor_ID= teaches_ID;",
      "choice1": "Select name,course_id from teaches,instructor where instructor_id=course_id;",
      "choice2": "Select name, course_id from instructor natural join teaches;",
      "choice3": "Select name, course_id from instructor;",
      "choice4": "Select course_id from instructor join teaches;",
      "correct_ans": "Select name, course_id from instructor natural join teaches;",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 4,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following given statements possibly contains the error?",
      "choice1": "select * from emp where empid = 10003;",
      "choice2": "select empid from emp where empid = 10006;",
      "choice3": "select empid from emp;",
      "choice4": "select empid where empid = 1009 and Lastname = 'GELLER';",
      "correct_ans": "select empid where empid = 1009 and Lastname = 'GELLER';",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 5,
      "question_text": "In mathematical term Table is referred as?",
      "choice1": "Relation",
      "choice2": "Attribute",
      "choice3": "Tuple",
      "choice4": " Domain",
      "correct_ans": "Relation",
      "level": 1
    },
    {
      "question_id": 6,
      "question_text": " Which of the following is not a level of data abstraction?",
      "choice1": "Physical Level",
      "choice2": "Critical Level",
      "choice3": "Logical Level",
      "choice4": " View Level",
      "correct_ans": "Critical Level",
      "level": 1
    }
  ],
  "level2": [
    {
      "question_id": 7,
      "question_text": "Ready the Query carefully:\nSELECT emp_name\nFROM department\nWHERE dept_name LIKE ' _____ Computer Science';\nIn the above-given Query, which of the following can be placed in the Query's blank portion to select the \"dept_name\" that also contains Computer Science as its ending string?",
      "choice1": "&",
      "choice2": "_",
      "choice3": "%",
      "choice4": "$",
      "correct_ans": "%",
      "level": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 8,
      "question_text": "What do you mean by one to many relationships?",
      "choice1": "One class may have many teachers",
      "choice2": "One teacher can have many classes",
      "choice3": "Many classes may have many teachers",
      "choice4": "Many teachers may have many classes",
      "correct_ans": "One teacher can have many classes",
      "level": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 9,
      "question_text": "In the following Query, which of the following can be placed in the Query's blank portion to display the salary from highest to lowest amount, and sorting the employs name alphabetically?\nSELECT *\nFROM instructor\nORDER BY salary ____, name ___;",
      "choice1": "Ascending, Descending",
      "choice2": "Asc, Desc",
      "choice3": "Desc, Asc",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Desc, Asc",
      "level": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 10,
      "question_text": "The given Query can be replaced with ____________:\nSELECT name\nFROM instructor1\nWHERE salary <= 100000 AND salary >= 90000;",
      "choice1": "SELECT name\nFROM instructor1\nWHERE salary BETWEEN 100000 AND 90000",
      "choice2": "SELECT name\nFROM instructor|\nWHERE salary BETWEEN 90000 AND 100000;",
      "choice3": "SELECT name\nFROM instructor1\nWHERE salary BETWEEN 90000 AND 100000;",
      "choice4": "SELECT name\nFROM instructor!\nWHERE salary <= 90000 AND salary>=100000;",
      "correct_ans": "SELECT name\nFROM instructor1\nWHERE salary BETWEEN 90000 AND 100000",
      "level": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 11,
      "question_text": "A Database Management System is a type of _________software.",
      "choice1": "It is a type of system software",
      "choice2": "It is a kind of application software",
      "choice3": "It is a kind of general software",
      "choice4": "Both A and C",
      "correct_ans": "It is a type of system software",
      "level": 2
    },
    {
      "question_id": 12,
      "question_text": "The term 'FAT' stands for_____",
      "choice1": "File Allocation Tree",
      "choice2": "File Allocation Table",
      "choice3": "File Allocation Graph",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "File Allocation Table",
      "level": 2
    }
  ],
  "level3": [
    {
      "question_id": 13,
      "question_text": "Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by FAT?",
      "choice1": "8GB",
      "choice2": "4GB",
      "choice3": "4TB",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "4GB",
      "level": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 14,
      "question_text": "The term 'NTFS' refers to which one of the following?",
      "choice1": "New Technology File System",
      "choice2": "New Tree File System",
      "choice3": "New Table type File System",
      "choice4": "Both A and C",
      "correct_ans": "New Technology File System",
      "level": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 15,
      "question_text": "Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by NTFS?",
      "choice1": "4GB",
      "choice2": "16TB",
      "choice3": "64TB",
      "choice4": "8TB",
      "correct_ans": "4GB",
      "level": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 16,
      "question_text": "A huge collection of the information or data accumulated from several different sources is known as ________:",
      "choice1": "Data Management",
      "choice2": "Data Mining",
      "choice3": "Data Warehouse",
      "choice4": "Both B and C",
      "correct_ans": "Data Warehouse",
      "level": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 17,
      "question_text": "What is SQL?",
      "choice1": "Structured Query Language",
      "choice2": "Standard Query Language",
      "choice3": "System Query Language",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Structured Query Language",
      "level": 3
    },
    {
      "question_id": 18,
      "question_text": "Which of the following can be used to extract or filter the data & information from the data warehouse?",
      "choice1": "Data redundancy",
      "choice2": "Data recovery tool",
      "choice3": "Data mining",
      "choice4": "Both B and C",
      "correct_ans": "Data mining",
      "level": 3
    }
  ],
  "level4": [
    {
      "question_id": 19,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following refers to the copies of the same data (or information) occupying the memory space at multiple places.",
      "choice1": "Data Repository",
      "choice2": "Data Inconsistency",
      "choice3": "Data Mining",
      "choice4": "Data Redundancy",
      "correct_ans": "Data Redundancy",
      "level": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 20,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following refers to the 'data about data'?",
      "choice1": "Directory",
      "choice2": "Sub Data",
      "choice3": "Warehouse",
      "choice4": "Meta Data",
      "correct_ans": "Meta Data",
      "level": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 21,
      "question_text": "Which of the following refers to the level of data abstraction that describes exactly how the data actually stored?",
      "choice1": "Conceptual Level",
      "choice2": "Physical Level",
      "choice3": "File Level",
      "choice4": "Logical Level",
      "correct_ans": "Physical Level",
      "level": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 22,
      "question_text": "To which of the following the term 'DBA' referred?",
      "choice1": "Data Bank Administrator",
      "choice2": "Database Administrator",
      "choice3": "Data Administrator",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Database Administrator",
      "level": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 23,
      "question_text": "In general, a file is basically a collection of all related______.",
      "choice1": "Rows & Columns",
      "choice2": "Fields",
      "choice3": "Database",
      "choice4": "Records",
      "correct_ans": "Records",
      "level": 4
    },
    {
      "question_id": 24,
      "question_text": "The term 'Data' refers to:",
      "choice1": "The electronic representation of the information (or data)",
      "choice2": "Basic information",
      "choice3": "Row Facts and figures",
      "choice4": "Both A and C",
      "correct_ans": "Row Facts and figures",
      "level": 4
    }
  ],
  "level5": [
    {
      "question_id": 25,
      "question_text": "Rows of a relation are known as the _______.",
      "choice1": "Degree",
      "choice2": "Tuples",
      "choice3": "Entity",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "All of the above",
      "level": 5
    },
    {
      "question_id": 26,
      "question_text": "Which of the following refers to the number of tuples in a relation?",
      "choice1": "Entity",
      "choice2": "Column",
      "choice3": "Cardinality",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Cardinality",
      "level": 5
    },
    {
      "question_id": 27,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following is a type of Data Manipulation Command?",
      "choice1": "Create",
      "choice2": "Alter",
      "choice3": "Delete",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Delete",
      "level": 5
    },
    {
      "question_id": 28,
      "question_text": "Which of the following command is a type of Data Definition language command?",
      "choice1": "Create",
      "choice2": "Update",
      "choice3": "Delete",
      "choice4": "Merge",
      "correct_ans": "Create",
      "level": 5
    },
    {
      "question_id": 29,
      "question_text": "Which of the following is a top-down approach in which the entity's higher level can be divided into two lower sub-entities?",
      "choice1": "Aggregation",
      "choice2": "Generalization",
      "choice3": "Specialization",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Specialization",
      "level": 5
    },
    {
      "question_id": 30,
      "question_text": "In which one of the following, the multiple lower entities are grouped (or combined) together to form a single higher-level entity?",
      "choice1": "Specialization",
      "choice2": "Generalization",
      "choice3": "Aggregation",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Generalization",
      "level": 5
    }
  ],
  "level6": [
    {
      "question_id": 31,
      "question_text": "In a relation database, every tuple divided into the fields is known as the______.",
      "choice1": "Queries",
      "choice2": "Domains",
      "choice3": "Relations",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Domains",
      "level": 6
    },
    {
      "question_id": 32,
      "question_text": "The term 'TCL' stands for_____.",
      "choice1": "Ternary Control Language",
      "choice2": "Transmission Control Language",
      "choice3": "Transaction Central Language",
      "choice4": "Transaction Control Language",
      "correct_ans": "Transaction Control Language",
      "level": 6
    },
    {
      "question_id": 33,
      "question_text": "What is C++?",
      "choice1": "Programming Language",
      "choice2": "Scripting Language",
      "choice3": "Markup Language",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Programming Language",
      "level": 6
    },
    {
      "question_id": 34,
      "question_text": "In the relational table, which of the following can also be represented by the term 'attribute'?",
      "choice1": "Entity",
      "choice2": "Row",
      "choice3": "Column",
      "choice4": "Both B &C",
      "correct_ans": "Column",
      "level": 6
    },
    {
      "question_id": 35,
      "question_text": "Which of the following refers to the number of attributes in a relation?",
      "choice1": "Degree",
      "choice2": "Row",
      "choice3": "Column",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Degree",
      "level": 6
    },
    {
      "question_id": 36,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following refers to the horizontal partitioning of a table?",
      "choice1": "Specialization",
      "choice2": "Generalization",
      "choice3": "Horizontal Fragmentation",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Horizontal Fragmentation",
      "level": 6
    }
  ],


  "level7": [
    {
      "question_id": 37,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following command is used to delete the existing row in a table?",
      "choice1": "Delete",
      "choice2": "Update",
      "choice3": "Insert",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Delete",
      "level": 7
    },
    {
      "question_id": 38,
      "question_text": "What is JSON?",
      "choice1": "JavaScript Object Notation",
      "choice2": "JavaScript Oriented Notation",
      "choice3": "JavaScript Order Notation",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "JavaScript Object Notation",
      "level": 7
    },
    {
      "question_id": 39,
      "question_text": "Which of the following commands is used to save any transaction permanently into the database?",
      "choice1": "Commit",
      "choice2": "Rollback",
      "choice3": "Savepoint",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Commit",
      "level": 7
    },
    {
      "question_id": 40,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following commands is used for removing (or deleting) a relation from the SQL database?",
      "choice1": "Delete",
      "choice2": "Drop",
      "choice3": "Remove",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Drop",
      "level": 7
    },
    {
      "question_id": 41,
      "question_text": "What is C#?",
      "choice1": "Programming Language",
      "choice2": "Scripting Language",
      "choice3": "Markup Language",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Programming Language",
      "level": 7
    },
    {
      "question_id": 42,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following commands is used to restore the database to the last committed state?",
      "choice1": "Savepoint",
      "choice2": "Rollback",
      "choice3": "Commit",
      "choice4": "Both A & B",
      "correct_ans": "Rollback",
      "level": 7
    }
  ],
  "level8": [
    {
      "question_id": 43,
      "question_text": "What is SVG?",
      "choice1": "Scalable Vector Graphics",
      "choice2": "Scalable Video Graphics",
      "choice3": "System Vector Graphics",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Scalable Vector Graphics",
      "level": 8
    },
    {
      "question_id": 44,
      "question_text": "Which of the following in not Outer join?",
      "choice1": "Left outer join",
      "choice2": "Right outer join",
      "choice3": "Full outer join",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "All of the above",
      "level": 8
    },
    {
      "question_id": 45,
      "question_text": "The database management system can be considered as the collection of ______ that enables us to create and maintain the database.",
      "choice1": "Translators",
      "choice2": "Programs",
      "choice3": "Keys",
      "choice4": "Language activity",
      "correct_ans": "Programs",
      "level": 8
    },
    {
      "question_id": 46,
      "question_text": "The term \"DFD\" stands for?",
      "choice1": "Data file diagram",
      "choice2": "Data flow document",
      "choice3": "Data flow diagram",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Data flow diagram",
      "level": 8
    },
    {
      "question_id": 47,
      "question_text": "What is Kotlin?",
      "choice1": "Programming Language",
      "choice2": "Scripting Language",
      "choice3": "Markup Language",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Programming Language",
      "level": 8
    },
    {
      "question_id": 48,
      "question_text": "Which of the following refers to the collection of information stored in a database at a specific time?",
      "choice1": "Independence",
      "choice2": "Instance of the database",
      "choice3": "Data domain",
      "choice4": "Schema",
      "correct_ans": "Instance of the database",
      "level": 8
    }
  ],
  "level9": [
    {
      "question_id": 49,
      "question_text": "The term \"Data independence\" refers to____",
      "choice1": "Data is defined separately and not included in the programs",
      "choice2": "Programs are not dependent on the logical attributes of the data",
      "choice3": "Programs are not dependent on the physical attributes of the data",
      "choice4": "None Of These",
      "correct_ans": "Data is defined separately and not included in the programs",
      "level": 9
    },
    {
      "question_id": 50,
      "question_text": "Which of the following is not binary operation?",
      "choice1": " Union",
      "choice2": "Project",
      "choice3": "Set Difference",
      "choice4": " Cartesian Product",
      "correct_ans": " Project",
      "level": 9
    },
    {
      "question_id": 51,
      "question_text": "What is the relation calculus?",
      "choice1": "It is a kind of procedural language",
      "choice2": "It is a non-procedural language",
      "choice3": "It is a high-level language",
      "choice4": "It is Data Definition language",
      "correct_ans": "It is a non-procedural language",
      "level": 9
    },
    {
      "question_id": 52,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following refers to the total view of the database content?",
      "choice1": "Conceptual view",
      "choice2": "Physical view",
      "choice3": "Internal view",
      "choice4": "External view",
      "correct_ans": "Conceptual view",
      "level": 9
    },
    {
      "question_id": 53,
      "question_text": "For what purpose is DML provided?",
      "choice1": "Addition of new structure in the database",
      "choice2": "Manipulation & processing of the database",
      "choice3": "Definition of the physical structure of the database system",
      "choice4": "All of the above",
      "correct_ans": "Manipulation & processing of the database",
      "level": 9
    },
    {
      "question_id": 54,
      "question_text": "The term \"ODBC\" stands for_____",
      "choice1": "Oral database connectivity",
      "choice2": "Oracle database connectivity",
      "choice3": "Open database connectivity",
      "choice4": "Object database connectivity",
      "correct_ans": "Open database connectivity",
      "level": 9
    }
  ],
  "level10": [
    {
      "question_id": 55,
      "question_text": "The architecture of a database can be viewed as the ________",
      "choice1": "One level",
      "choice2": "Two-level",
      "choice3": "Three-level",
      "choice4": "Four level",
      "correct_ans": "Three-level",
      "level": 10
    },
    {
      "question_id": 56,
      "question_text": "In the relation model, the relations are generally termed as ________",
      "choice1": "Tuples",
      "choice2": "Attributes",
      "choice3": "Rows",
      "choice4": "Tables",
      "correct_ans": "Tables",
      "level": 10
    },
    {
      "question_id": 57,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following commands is used to modify a column inside a table?",
      "choice1": "Drop",
      "choice2": "Update",
      "choice3": "Alter",
      "choice4": "Set",
      "correct_ans": "Alter",
      "level": 10
    },
    {
      "question_id": 58,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following is commonly used to define the overall design of the database?",
      "choice1": "Application program",
      "choice2": "Data definition language",
      "choice3": "Schema",
      "choice4": "Source code",
      "correct_ans": "Schema",
      "level": 10
    },
    {
      "question_id": 59,
      "question_text": "Which one of the following keywords is used to find out the number of values in a column?",
      "choice1": "TOTAL",
      "choice2": "COUNT",
      "choice3": "SUM",
      "choice4": "ADD",
      "correct_ans": "COUNT",
      "level": 10
    },
    {
      "question_id": 60,
      "question_text": "Which of the following levels is considered as the level closest to the end-users?",
      "choice1": "Internal Level",
      "choice2": "External Level",
      "choice3": "Conceptual Level",
      "choice4": "Physical Level",
      "correct_ans": "External Level",
      "level": 10
    }
  ]
}
